<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>finniweb</title>
    <description>My voluntary year in Canada... On this blog I document my time in Canada and...
</description>
    <link>http://finniweb.de/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://finniweb.de/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 23:19:17 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 23:19:17 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Midterm Report</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During the last weeks we have looked over the applications for my successor at the Morning Glory School. It was very interesting for me to be on the other side of the application process.&lt;br /&gt;
Together with the requirement to write a mid term report to the “Friends of Waldorf Education”, it also made me realize how quickly time has passed and how limited my remaining time in Canada is...&lt;br /&gt;
Here is my midterm report for you to read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Midterm report by Finn Hansch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;February 14, 2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The “Morning Glory School” is a small little private school with about 30 students. As a Waldorf oriented School with a limited budget we try to give the students the experiences of a Waldorf education.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a former Waldorf student I am now working as a Waldorf teacher. I’m teaching German and Games (Sports) and help in the preschool as well as in the Kindergarden. My working hours are from 8:30am until 3:00pm.&lt;br /&gt;
In the morning I help either in the Preschool or in the Kindergarden by preparing snack or supervising the kids, giving the teachers a break.&lt;br /&gt;
Afterwards I alternate with teaching German and Games in the three Grades (Grades 1-2, 3-5, &amp;amp; 6-8). From the very beginning I have been on my own while teaching. The first two months as a teacher I had to learn to keep the class under control and how to build up some authority. Nevertheless, due to my age and my special role I could keep a different relationship with the students. That helped me a lot to motivate the students and convey the fun of learning to them.&lt;br /&gt;
Like other teachers will probably experience too, I still have to face the continual struggle of encouraging silence and concentration in class. But after the first half of the year I don’t feel that overwhelmed by it anymore.&lt;br /&gt;
Something that I still struggle with is preparing for the german lessons. To unite the different age groups and the different language skills is not easy. On top of that there are a lot of new students who have never taken german lessons in school before. To help those students on their first steps while keeping it interesting for the others has been a constant challenge and I am sure it will stay like that for the months to come.&lt;br /&gt;
These experiences have shown me how difficult it is to learn or teach a foreign language. At the same time it has woken a passion in me to learn more languages (I hope that I am also passing that enthusiasm to my students…).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since we have chosen my successor for the next school year already I will also look into preparing the next years volunteer and hopefully give her a good start in the next school year (a help I have missed in my first steps of this experience).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As the only volunteer at the school, I have the great possibility to expand my english and to connect more with my surroundings. Despite the  cultural differences being small there are differences and I am getting to know a different world. On the other hand I can also give something special back to this culture myself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I expect the second half of my voluntary service to be less demanding because I have gotten used to my occupation and it isn’t taking up all my time and energy anymore. Therefore I want to spend the time ahead of me, here in Canada, focusing more on my personal goals. For though I will still gain new experiences working at the school, I can now again approach some hobbies and projects of my own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://finniweb.de/Midterm-report</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://finniweb.de/Midterm-report</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Half way mark</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everybody!
We have completed the second week of the second term. Not much has happened since I wrote last. I realized I have never actually told you much about my work! So before I start apologizing again I’ll just give you a quick catch up…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am working from 8:30am until 3 o’clock in the afternoon! Except for Fridays when we end at half past 12.&lt;br /&gt;
Every day I usually help in either the Preschool or the Kindergarten and teach all of the other grades in German or Games. So I am pretty much everywhere every day and obviously right in the middle of most of what is happening. That is not very difficult anyways because the school has only about 30 students in total!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday and Wednesday mornings I help out in the Preschool. I prepare snack and do whatever there is to do! After a couple of weeks the Preschool teacher and I have become a pretty good team and things usually work quite smoothly. (Not to mention that there are only four children ages 3 to 4 in the class).&lt;br /&gt;
After the kids “graduate” from Preschool they go to Kindergarten. Because they are close in age the Preschool and Kindergarten classes often join together for field trips or on Fridays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday’s and Thursday’s after the daily morning walk (with the older kids), I start out helping with math in Grades 3-5.* Since last week the class has been split in half for math only so that I teach the younger ones (currently devision) while the older kids learn advanced math with the class teacher.&lt;br /&gt;
We are planning on replacing the morning walks on those 2 days with a morning run (led by me) because most of the kids are very active throughout the day and will probably benefit from burning more energy in the morning.&lt;br /&gt;
Then I join the Kindergarten and eat snack with the kids before we go outside to play. That gives the Kindergarten teacher a little break on at least two of the weekdays.&lt;br /&gt;
It is of course easier said than done. Before snack we have to tidy up the room and get everybody to help (usually the biggest hassle).&lt;br /&gt;
Afterwards we have a little nap and then go to wash our hands for snack. Snacktime works out very well most of the time although the kids need constant reminding to stay at the table and eat their food.&lt;br /&gt;
Towards the end of snack we all make little nests with our hands for “Poppy Bird”, (hopefully spelled right… but then again it doesn’t really matter does it?) a little felted purple bird tied to a string. I then fly Poppy Bird around the table to sit in everybody’s nest and the bird gives one child a kiss. The kissed child is then allowed to snuff out the candle accompanied by a little song sung by everybody. That of course is often connected with unfulfilled expectations and little jealousies because Poppy Bird can only kiss one child per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then comes the logistical challenge of getting the table gnomes to clear and clean the table, the water washers to wash the dishes and the sweeping sprites to sweep, preferably at the same time and without me heaving to chase any of them.&lt;br /&gt;
When everybody is done their tasks we head outside for some outdoor play time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy being with the “little” kids. Though they seem to often have problems with sharing or taking turns, most of the time they play very well together, which has improved as more children have joined the class.&lt;br /&gt;
They all seem to like me well and they are still at the age where they show their feelings openly! It is a great experience and often brightens my day when I enter the room and most of them interrupt their play to greet me with a hug or to let everybody know “FINN IS HERE”!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are my mornings.
In the afternoon I alternate between Games and German with all the other classes. But I’ll leave that for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more thing I wanted to mention though.
Before Christmas we did a beautiful Advent Spiral. I had almost forgotten that I had done something like that while I was in Kindergarten myself.&lt;br /&gt;
The Advent Spiral is made out of fir branches and in the middle there is a big candle.&lt;br /&gt;
The children walk through slowly and calmly, following the spiral holding a candle placed into an apple functioning as a candle holder. In the middle they light their candle and then place the apple along the spiral on the next free spot. The whole event takes place in darkness and silence accompanied by some calm and quiet music.&lt;br /&gt;
It was marvellous… I took some pictures afterwards and put them into the gallery for you to see yourselves!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since Morning Glory School is only a small school, grades 1&amp;amp;2 are joined together as well as grades 3,4&amp;amp;5 and 6,7&amp;amp;8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://finniweb.de/Half-way-mark</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://finniweb.de/Half-way-mark</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Winter holidays</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Time flies by! Fall ended, first advent, St. Nicolas came and left, Christmas was knocking on our doors! And all the following stuff!&lt;br /&gt;
It was a great time but I am also looking forward to go back to school on Monday!&lt;br /&gt;
I hope you all had a great time and are now freshly energized for the coming year.&lt;br /&gt;
However I wanted to tell you a little about my holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last weeks before Christmas the kids became excited for Christmas! That obviously didn’t make things easier in class. So when the break finally started it felt a little overdue but also came very sudden. The time of advent just went by without any real signs of Christmas. I guess that is not exactly true because when it started getting dark earlier you could see a lot of glowing christmas decorations in the front of and on many houses! Of course there was the Christmas faire at the Morning Glory School but that was about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Christmas came even more sudden and left me with my christmas feelings as unprepared as never before!&lt;br /&gt;
On Christmas Eve (the 24th of December) we had a family dinner while Santa didn’t deliver until the next morning! As quick as Christmas came it was as quick it was over and forgotten.
On New Years eve I went to Duncan (approximately 100km south of Qualicum Beach) to celebrate the new year with some other volunteers my age on the Island.&lt;br /&gt;
It was nice to be around people my age again. It was a little chaotic in the morning though and I couldn’t get the bus in time. So to still get home the same day I decided to Hitchhike home! That was another thing on my bucket-list anyway and here on the island it seems to be still a used form of transportation.&lt;br /&gt;
Anyways, I didn’t even had to wait long until I got picked up and brought back home!&lt;br /&gt;
The last few days I struggled a little with a missing structure (since I still have holidays until Monday) and now I’m trying to get everything set up for the coming term!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://finniweb.de/Winter-holidays</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://finniweb.de/Winter-holidays</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Maple leaves are falling</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, it’s time again...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last few weeks were pretty busy.&lt;br /&gt;
In addition to the regular stress a couple of other things happened. Three weeks ago I went with my family on a short trip to Ucluelet, a little fishing town in the north of the island.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
On our way there the weather did exactly what it is supposed to do in fall! It was pouring down.&lt;br /&gt;
But like I said that is nothing unusual here on the west coast.
After the rain had faded out I went to explore the surrounding. The fishy, salty air made the image of the little fishing harbour perfect.&lt;br /&gt;
The “busy” part of the town is the main road with a couple of stores. Eventually it started raining again and I rescued myself into a little cafe. After an expensive piece of brownie cake I performed some magic tricks.&lt;br /&gt;
Later that day I tried to get a great view of the sunset… of course it was super foggy and cloudy, due to the bad weather and I didn’t even get a glimpse of any sun at all. It was still very beautiful.&lt;br /&gt;
During the short trip I fell in love with the little town, it’s people and it’s two radio channels…&lt;br /&gt;
The next morning we walked the trail called “the wild pacific trail” to the Lighthouse of the peninsular before we had to head back home. (I have placed some photos into the &lt;a href=&quot;/gallery&quot;&gt;gallery&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the probably biggest events was of course Halloween! How could it have been any different. It still surprised me to see the effort many people prepared themselves to the night.&lt;br /&gt;
At home I never payed Halloween much attention. Here I saw it lined up with Easter, Christmas and the birthday. Everyone goes crazy and houses are converted into “haunted houses”. It was so exciting that I forgot to take any pictures.&lt;br /&gt;
Good for us we got a week of holidays on the week before halloween so I could celebrate Halloween on the mainland in Vancouver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first days of the holidays I spent recovering from the school and a light flu. I couldn’t believe it but the little break did a lot of change. The last week went great and I felt a lot more RELAXED and more self-confident in working with the students. It feels like I really learned some practical things in the last two month. At least I don’t feel totally overwhelmed when I’m teaching anymore. Now “solved” that I have to tackle the greater challenge: “how to teach a bunch of kids a foreign language!?” But I think that I’m on a good way there too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday we went to the “Englishman River Falls”. I asked myself if there are any comparable waterfalls in Germany. But surely they are not as beautiful. If you are looking at the photos you need to imagine a deafening rushing. Other than that there is not much to say… Oh one thing did come to my mind! “Breathtaking nature 15 minutes from home”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I am sitting here with Zeus the always hungry cat and… whop! Now he jumped off and walks up to his food dish to check if it really is empty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m enjoying the next week with a lot of sunshine!!!! A week without rain! That is rare here in fall, winter or spring!
But enough about weather, I wish you a nice November and I’m going to get back to you! At some point.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://finniweb.de/Maple-leaves-are-falling</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://finniweb.de/Maple-leaves-are-falling</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It’s been a month</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a while, a month to be exact! Let me explain what took me so long!&lt;br /&gt;
After I arrived I lived with Mickey and Eli and had a great time though it was a little difficult for me in the beginning of getting used to my new surrounding and meanwhile teaching young and old kids how to speak german! But at some point things felt great and I was really confident and happy! I had just cleaned my room and arranged everything and started feeling home when the fleas started to attack me. Our first move was too buy some poison and spray it in my room to get rid of the fleas! It didn’t work and after a couple of days the “happy hopping” was back!&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After another try I gave up trying to exterminate the fleas and was looking for another room without carpet. Unfortunately there was none available! Since I couldn’t live with the fleas I had to make the decision of changing my address. I hated the idea of a new host family and it took me a while to actually make the call and tell Micky about it. It was tough and we tried to bring it behind us as fast as possible so I moved in the middle of the night.&lt;br /&gt;
Fortunately Mickey and I could sort things out and we still get along very well!&lt;br /&gt;
I also got lucky that my new host family is as nice and that they also live in Qualicum beach.&lt;br /&gt;
Of course I had to start from beginning and try to settle in a second time! That kept me very busy while my growing personal ambitions towards my lessons took their tribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I feel more comfortable with my home situation as well as my daily routine I’m looking forward to other stuff! I want to explore the surrounding, meet some people my age and get some hobbies going!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this is a rather short update for the long time I didn’t write but from now on I will keep up the writing and hopefully get the gallery to work soon! In any way I will soon tell you about my schedule at the school and how things are working out for me here on Vancouver Island!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://finniweb.de/It's-been-a-month</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://finniweb.de/It's-been-a-month</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Entry into Canada</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally I managed to publish this post! A big THANK YOU to those of you patiently waiting.
My voyage here was a little adventure. It all started at Hamburg airport from where I was taking the flight to Munich and from there to Toronto!&lt;br /&gt;
It took nine hours to get to Toronto and it was a smooth flight! However with my arrival in Toronto trouble startet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/image/leaving.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;my image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I had to get my luggage from the baggage claim and check it in again I had to leave the security area! In order to do that I had to get to the immigration office to get my Visa printed into my passport!&lt;br /&gt;
It took me 2 hours to wait in the line and in that time not only my connecting flight but also the next flight to Victoria had already departed. This left me with two choices. Either to wait until next morning and take the first flight to Victoria or to go on standby for a flight to Vancouver and fly over from there the next morning!&lt;br /&gt;
I chose to stay in Toronto for the night and finally managed to inform someone that I wouldn’t show up in Victoria until morning.&lt;br /&gt;
But the Adventure didn’t end yet! Arriving in Victoria I had to get to Nanaimo by bus because everyone was working and not able to pick me up! So I hitchhiked from the Airport into town to take the bus. There I had to trick the ticket seller by slightly lifting up my luggage to make it look like it weights 2 pounds less on the scale than it did.
In Nanaimo I had to wait a little more and then I finally - after a sleepless 48 hours trip - met my “new family” Mickey and her lovely son Eli (six years old) and got taken into my new home!&lt;br /&gt;
The funny thing about my trip is that I tricked the jet lag  by not sleeping at all…  &lt;br /&gt;
The next day I was invited to the first staff meeting of the school in which I’ll be teaching the next year and I met the other teachers!&lt;br /&gt;
The rest of the time I was busy getting comfortable in my new surrounding! Being here is overwhelming! I’ve seen deer just walking beside the car and blocking the road. The landscape is fantastic and we are living at the end of the nice and not too small town, Qualicum Beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow will be my first day at work! I’m excited to see how it will go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll try to report back soon with new updates, so stay tuned until then!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://finniweb.de/Entry-into-Canada</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://finniweb.de/Entry-into-Canada</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Well prepared</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During the last two weeks I were at the preparation seminar for my “Volutary Year Abroad”! The seminar definitely overcame my expectations!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
Starting with a group of more than 50 participants we were separated into two smaller groups though we still did many activities as the big group. Under those 50 participants I only met great people. Despite the difficulties of getting to know over 50 people in just 9 days I became friends with most! In addition to the great Activities there were some discourses and workshops which taught me lots of new stuff and depend other knowledge of mine. Trough feedback exercises in which we were practicing criticising and to handle critic from others I also became more self-confident. Though I can say that I didn’t have much anxieties regarding my voluntary year I came back more self-assured like I got rid of anxieties I wasn’t even aware of.
Like most of us I would have wished to depart from there right away but my last few days in Hamburg are pretty much full anyway....&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://finniweb.de/Well-prepared</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://finniweb.de/Well-prepared</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>finniweb is online</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally the coding is done and the blog is ready for action!&lt;br /&gt;
I will continue to upgrade the website by adding features you’re hopefully not missing until they are there…!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I’m going to visit the (lets call it) preparation camp for my social year on Tuesday it is just in time!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
On this website there are some cool features I’m very proud of.  You might not realize them when visiting… thats why I’m listing them below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all it is a responsive site! that means you can display it correctly with any device without making the content look ridiculous! (try resizing your browser window horizontally and you’ll see!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly finniweb is bilingual which is great (check out the german version at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.finniweb.de&quot;&gt;www.finniweb.de&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And third: the search function may not be as precise or user oriented as google but it gets the job done (one of the features you weren’t supposed to miss until there…) but the cool part of it is the search bar itself and it’s behaviour (you should definitely check it out! just click it!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may or may not experience some minor mistakes on this website! I hope I found and fixed them all but there is always something to do… (especially Firefox gave me a hard time)!&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve run and tested this site with the Browsers Safari, Firefox, Google Chrome and Opera as well as the mobile iOS versions of Safari! If you happen to use Internet Explorer (especially versions before IE9)  you probably will encounter a lot of problems and graphically wrong aligned content since I didn’t test my site with it (due to it’s versions only run on windows). In that case you might want to upgrade to a different browser anyway!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you encounter any problems or have any suggestions please let me me know about by &lt;a href=&quot;support@finniweb.com&quot;&gt;mailing me at support@finniweb.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy my site,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;finni&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://finniweb.de/finniweb-is-online</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://finniweb.de/finniweb-is-online</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
